<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Nop Jiarathanakul]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nop Jiarathanakul online portfolio. I love making things, especially beautiful 3D applications. I like WebGL, shaders, three.js, typography, and indie rock. My background is in computer graphics, games, and animation.]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 05:24:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[New Website!]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post marks the launch of a new long overdue website! I released my current website at  https://www.iamnop.com/  a long time ago, but it…]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2018-08-30-new-website</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2018-08-30-new-website</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post marks the launch of a new long overdue website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio/new-website.png&quot; alt=&quot;www.iamnop.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I released my current website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iamnop.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.iamnop.com/&lt;/a&gt; a long time ago, but it was practically a placeholder with almost no content. Now I’ve rebuilt it from the ground up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; and a powerful site generator &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a good while (a month or so) to finally complete this project, as I was learning a lot of new libraries along the way. I was also being a smartypants and jumped ahead to Gatsby v2, which is still in beta. I ended up writing and rewriting a lot of throwaway code as the beta still had a ton of moving parts and bugs. However, the Gatsby community is very active and has been very helpful in helping me get through the blockers. Thanks guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will probably be writing more about the development process later. In the meantime, if you’re curious you can check out the code on Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nopjia/gatsby-blog&quot;&gt;https://github.com/nopjia/gatsby-blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hire Me need a graphics guy? Looking for hand-crafted, high-end, interactive 3D experiences for your website or product? I’m available for…]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com//hire</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iamnop.com//hire</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 01:35:46 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Hire Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;need a graphics guy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for hand-crafted, high-end, interactive 3D experiences for your website or product? I’m available for consulting, freelance, and contract work.
Based in San Francisco Bay Area.
Available for both on-site and remote projects.
Please reach out to me directly for any inquiries!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WebGL Offerings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom 3D viewers and product configurators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data visualization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photorealistic rendering (PBR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Particle simulations (GPGPU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music visualizers, VR, shaders, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-stack web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical artist, animation, and 3D asset pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game prototyping and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics:&lt;/strong&gt; WebGL, Three.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web:&lt;/strong&gt; HTML, Javascript, CSS, Node.js, React.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3D Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Maya, MEL, Python, Unity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iamnop.com/jiarathanakul.pdf&quot;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebGL GPU Particles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Weekend project I started about a month ago, a WebGL GPU particle simulator, simulating 1 million particles at 60 fps! Live code:  http…]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2014-06-08-webgl-gpu-particles</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2014-06-08-webgl-gpu-particles</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Weekend project I started about a month ago, a WebGL GPU particle simulator, simulating 1 million particles at 60 fps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio/webglparticles_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;WebGL GPU Particles&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live code: &lt;a href=&quot;http://iamnop.com/particles-mrt/&quot;&gt;http://iamnop.com/particles-mrt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click to set the gravity point. Hold Alt for Maya camera controls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Requires webgl&lt;em&gt;draw&lt;/em&gt;buffers extension. More info on how to enable.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IyM0YxizdnY&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IyM0YxizdnY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nopjia/particles-mrt&quot;&gt;https://github.com/nopjia/particles-mrt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo can be broken into two parts: 1) the compute and 2) the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compute part is where most of the work happens to simulate the particles. There are three textures representing each of the particles states: position, velocity, and color. Each particle is then represented by a UV coordinate into these textures, essentially a pixel, where its states are stored. A point to note here is that the position and velocity textures have to be float textures in order to represent the large range of numbers. At first I tried scaling up the range of a regular byte texture but there just wasn’t enough resolution for the simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heavy lifting is done through a GLSL shader which I use as a compute shader. It reads in the three state textures (nearest filtering of course, wouldn’t make sense otherwise) and performs a simulation step. Then it writes the results back to the corresponding framebuffers, all at once thanks to the webgl&lt;em&gt;draw&lt;/em&gt;buffers extension. Because OpenGL doesn’t allow writing to the same textures that you are reading from, I needed a duplicate set of framebuffers/textures to swap between every frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view part is responsible for the actual drawing of the particles onto the screen. The number of particles is determined by the size of the compute textures (e.g., 1024x1024 textures would give us ~1 million particles!) As mentioned earlier, each particle is represented only by a pixel location in the state textures, so all I had to do for each vertex is to submit a UV coordinate. Then in the vertex shader, I simply use the UV to look up its position from the position texture and its color from the color texture. (The velocity texture is only used by the compute shader to run the simulation and isn’t used here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure smoothness, the simulation runs on a different loop than the rendering. The simulation step has to run at a fixed time step, independent of the frame rate, otherwise a variable time step would introduce irregularities in the simulation, which becomes quite apparent when there are a million particles. Putting the simulation on a fixed update step not only produces smooth results but also allows for consistent results no matter the frame rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WIP!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress, and I’m planning to add more features. Most important is to add support for not having the webgl&lt;em&gt;draw&lt;/em&gt;buffers extension so any up-to-date browser can run this. Then I’m planning to add a few post-processing effects like ghost trails and bloom to make it look even more awesome. Finally, I’ll need better UI to expose more settings to play with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Note on Live Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not guaranteed to work on all machines! The demo is using a draft extension which might not be supported on your hardware. Here’s how to try to get it to work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the latest version of Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to chrome://flags/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable “WebGL Draft Extensions” (chrome://flags/#enable-webgl-draft-extensions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Windows, you might also need to enable D3D11 (chrome://flags/#enable-d3d11)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it doesn’t work, try again with Firefox? I’m sorry but I promise I will add support for no extension soon!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[CUDA Path Tracer]]></title><description><![CDATA[My last school project, ever! (Hopefully!) Github:  https://github.com/nopjia/tracer Video:  http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mbpqxlJHaBE This…]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2013-07-25-cuda-path-tracer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2013-07-25-cuda-path-tracer</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My last school project, ever! (Hopefully!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio/cudatracer_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CUDA Path Tracer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nopjia/tracer&quot;&gt;https://github.com/nopjia/tracer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mbpqxlJHaBE&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mbpqxlJHaBE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first ever attempt at writing a path tracer, and of course, making things real-time (or at least somewhat) is always more fun. It was something I’ve always wanted to do. I learned a whole lot about physically based rendering, for obvious reasons. But I also learned a lot about coding in CUDA and its in’s and out’s, which involved writing a lot of pure C code and writing nifty inline structs and functions for both host and device uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, the renderer doesn’t have fancy features, I’m quite happy with it. Despite the lack of acceleration structures, it still runs at ~20fps, and converges around 30 seconds, on my laptop. The next area of improvement would definitely be adding a kd-tree, in order to support larger scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as usual, I decided to make things interesting by making it interactive. Being able to easily modify the scene on the fly really makes it more fun and creates lots of interesting images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to the Github page for a whole lot more info!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive real-time path tracer in CUDA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Rendering Seminar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Pennsylvania, Spring 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebTube]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here is a long overdue post that I finally got around to write now that school is over! Over the weekend of January 18-20th, I attended the…]]></description><link>https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2013-05-16-webtube</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iamnop.com//posts/2013-05-16-webtube</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here is a long overdue post that I finally got around to write now that school is over! Over the weekend of January 18-20th, I attended the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2013s.pennapps.com&quot;&gt;Spring 2013 PennApps Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;, the largest student-run hackathon on the east coast, organized by no other than the University of Pennsylvania. Since this was to be my last PennApps Hackathon (this being my 5th time), I decided to have fun over the weekend, hang out with people, and do something fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made WebTube, a fun little web app that lets you browse the internet through the comfort of an old-school CRT TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reception turned out much better than I had expected. I came into the hackathon only to have some fun and not expecting anything. In the end, WebTube won 3rd place overall and Audience Choice Award!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ZUCyN6yvps&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ZUCyN6yvps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iamnop.com/webtube/&quot;&gt;https://www.iamnop.com/webtube/&lt;/a&gt; (must enable CSS Shaders flag in Chrome)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio/webtube_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WebTube&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core component of this web app is CSS Shaders, which allows access to programmable vertex and fragment shaders for HTML DOM elements. CSS Shaders are an extension to CSS Filters, which are a set of image filters available for CSS, such as grayscale, sepia, brightness/contrast, hue/saturation, etc. CSS Shaders are essentially custom filters that can be controlled through vertex and fragment shaders. This allows for a much greater freedom and very interesting CSS animations and CSS transitions. (See CSS FilterLab for live examples.) Please see related links below for more information related to CSS Shaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With understanding of CSS Shaders, WebTube is a very simple app. It has one main DOM for the screen, which allows for different modes, including web and SSH terminal. Multiple CSS transition rules are applied to the screen using CSS Shaders. The vertex shader warps the screen to produce the curvature and the fragment shader applies TV-like effects on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/devnet/html5/articles/css-shaders.html&quot;&gt;http://www.adobe.com/devnet/html5/articles/css-shaders.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html.adobe.com/webplatform/graphics/customfilters/cssfilterlab/&quot;&gt;http://html.adobe.com/webplatform/graphics/customfilters/cssfilterlab/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alteredqualia.com/css-shaders/article/&quot;&gt;http://alteredqualia.com/css-shaders/article/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dvcs.w3.org/hg/FXTF/raw-file/tip/filters/index.html#shading-language&quot;&gt;https://dvcs.w3.org/hg/FXTF/raw-file/tip/filters/index.html#shading-language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>